Dori Jacobson's Women's Rights Portfolio, 1977-1986
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Dori Jacobson women's rights portfolio
1977-1986
Jacobson, Dori
MS 279
1 box (.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Photographer and feminist. Includes photos of individual women and events, including women's rights actions in Illinois, the Equal Rights Amendment movement in Illinois, the National Organization for Women, New York anti-pornography rally, abortion rights and antinuclear events, and the March for Women's Lives, Washington, D.C.
Biographical Note
Dorothea (Dori) Jacobson was a freelance photographer who documented women's rights actions in Illinois, New York, and Washington, D.C. from 1977 to 1986.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
This collection consists of twenty-eight photographs by Dori Jacobson, including images of ERA rallies and marches held in June 1982, a 1984 Nuclear Freeze Rally in Chicago, and the 1986 March for Women's Lives in Washington D.C. Jacobson has captured several well-known women in her photographs, including Betty Ford, Helen Caldicott, Gloria Steinem, and Sonia Johnson.
Arrangement of the Collection
The photographs are arranged chronologically.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to collection are expected.
History of the Collection
These photographs were the gift of Dorothea Jacobson in 1986.
Search Terms
Antinuclear movement--United States--Photographs; Caldicott, Helen--Photographs; Demonstrations--United States--Photographs; Equal rights amendments--Illinois--Photographs; Feminists--United States--Photographs; Ford, Betty, 1918- --Photographs; Johnson, Sonia--Photographs; National Organization for Women--Photographs; Pro-choice movement--United States--Photographs; Steinem, Gloria--Photographs; Women photographers--United States; Jacobson, Dori
- Contents (Box 1)
- Photocopies of photographs (for research use) (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Gloria Steinem, March for ERA and International Women's Year Conference, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Gloria Steinem, New York, New York: Anti-pornography March, October 29, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gloria Steinem, Chicago, Illinois: National March for ERA, June 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Springfield, Illinois: ERA march and "Nott Rally," 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Springfield, Illinois: ERA Demonstration, June 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7-18)
  - Helen Caldicott, Chicago, Illinois: Nuclear Freeze Rally, October 13, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 19-22)
  - Chicago, Illinois: Nuclear Freeze Rally, October 1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Washington, D.C.: March for Women's Lives, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 24-27)